Hugo Blanco

Oracle Developer/DBA - ATT

Manhattan, NY - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Hugo-Blanco/7615e5c2d9f11195

Over eight years of management experience with extensive knowledge of Capital Markets, Portfolio Management, Derivatives, Emerging Markets, FOREX, and Commodities and M&A, Asset Management. Six years of software development both on the front and backend. I love to learn new skill thus I am in constant search of new technology. I like to work under pressure and have produced some of my best work during high pressure times. I also have experience in data science, deep learning and AI, Financial Modeling DCF Valuation, LBO Valuation.

Willing to relocate to: New York, NY

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oracle Developer/DBA

ATT - September 2016 to Present

Linux Admin, Sql SSIS developer, Iphone and Android tester, Oracle Dba, Oracle developer, Python developer and Tester, Veritas Administrator, Pen Tester, created Coded UI test cases with C#. Full Stack Development: MVC 5 and .Net Core (Razor, SignalR, Angular Js, Client and Server Side validation, EF). Full Deployment of RHEL 7 and Oracle 12c in an Enterprise environment. Worked with Fidelio ticketing system.

Oracle Developer/Data Modeler

Model Power Grid - October 2015 to August 2016

substations; create python and pearl scripts to solve day-to-day operations. SQL *plus, TOAD, Table functions, Entity relation modeling and design techniques, PL-SQL, CLI, PUTTY, PSCP. MongoDb administrator: Monitoring, Sharding, Replica sets, Indexing.

SQL BI Developer/Software Tester/DBA

TradeStation - April 2013 to October 2015

Use ETL process to extract data and run in SSIS package. DBA (Backups/Restore, Create SQL Jobs, Disaster recovery and Planning, Log Shipping, Database Mirroring and data Migration. Performance Tuning, Index Analysis, Replication, BCP, import and export data integration, sql server clusters. Handling of 20 TB database, SQL Load Generator, WholsActive. Selenium testing with Java and Python. Writing MDX queries, creating and customizing cubes using SSAS. Developing and designing report through SSRS, drill down, dashboards, etc. Use windows functions to derive complex sql store procedures. AWS (Dynamo, Redshift - Creating tables, Loading data, Managing Clusters, Snapshots, EC2 - Linux instances, RDS). Full Deployment of Hadoop environment to migrate sql data.

Software Developer/Oracle DBA

Ingham Retire Group - November 2011 to April 2013

Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition. Oracle: Logins, Schema Design, Gathering Statistics, Execution Plan, managing table space, standby/failover administration, Design and Maintain website, C# programming. Use python to run statistics via Canopy. Use Tableau and Crystal Reports to create workbooks to perform QTD, YTD Analysis as well as develop visualization and Dashboards. Create UNIX shell scripts to automate database operation.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Engineering in Computer Engineering

FLORIDAINTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY - Miami, FL 2011

SKILLS

AWS (2 years), BI (2 years), Linux (3 years), Python (3 years), Sql (4 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Skills

- Open Source: Linux, Hadoop, MongoDB, Javascript
- Network Communication: TCP/IP Stack, Cisco, Nomadix
- Microsoft Suite Office, SQL(2005 2016), Windows (2000 2012)
- Strong programming languages: C++, C#, JAVA, Python, R-Programming, Perl
- Agile and Water Fall environments (Kanban, Sprints, Spikes, JIRA)
- BI: ETL, SSIS, SSRS, SSAS
- · Cloud: AWS, Azure

Business Skills

- Outstanding presentation and communications skills.
- I have a swift knowledge of both computer and electrical engineer combined with a cross-functional background in finance and portfolio management.